Rain.
雨。
I've never liked rain.
我从来就不喜欢雨。
I know people say
我知道人们说
that rain is a blessing.
那场雨是一种祝福。
But for me…
但对我来说……
Dad!
爸爸！
rain
雨
always brings disaster.
总是带来灾难。
Time waits for no one.
时间不等人。
Akid,
阿基德，
you said
你说
today you'd be ready to share.
今天您已准备好分享。
Kabir.
卡比尔。
Do you believe that in this world,
你相信吗，在这个世界上，
some people can go back
有些人可以回去
in time?
及时？
Like time travel?
喜欢时间旅行吗？
Yes, Akid.
是的，阿基德。
Like time travel.
就像时间旅行。
Hold on, what's your point, Dad?
等等，爸爸，你到底想说什么？
You have to listen to me carefully.
你必须仔细听我说。
In our family
在我们的家庭中
once a person reaches 18, like you have,
一旦一个人年满 18 岁，就像你一样，
we can go back in time.
我们可以回到过去。
But only to go back to the past.
但只能回到过去。
Okay.
好的。
Can you explain clearly?
你能解释清楚吗？
Why don't you think of
你为什么不想想
numbers.
数字。
Any combination of numbers.
任意数字组合。
It can be as complicated as you want.
它可以按照你想要的复杂程度来。
Write them in your book.
把它们写在你的书里。
And then?
进而？
Your wife calls
你老婆打电话
to remind you to buy bread and eggs.
提醒你买面包和鸡蛋。
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
Okay,
好的，
I will buy them.
我会买它们。
-But how…? -Your assistant will enter
-但是如何……？-你的助手将进入
to inquire about the appointment with patient 29.
询问与 29 号患者的预约情况。
Come in.
进来。
Sorry to bother you, Doctor.
很抱歉打扰您，医生。
Appointment for patient 29 today.
今天为第 29 位患者预约。
Is that still on?
还在吗？
Let's push it to tomorrow.
就把它推迟到明天吧。
How did you…?
你怎么…？
And the number
以及数量
is 11911911.
是 11911911。
Correct?
正确的？
So you have…
所以你有……
I've gone back to a few minutes ago.
我又回到了几分钟前。
I knew your wife would call.
我知道你的妻子会打电话。
Your assistant would enter
你的助手会进入
and when I was back, I asked you myself
当我回来的时候，我亲自问你
about the numbers.
关于数字。
Now let me ask you.
现在让我问你。
How?
如何？
So you're ready to hear my story.
您已经准备好听我的故事了。
Dad.
爸爸。
What's wrong with you?
你这人怎么回事？
You've gone back.
你回去了。
I don't know why we have this ability.
我不知道我们为什么有这种能力。
Your grandfather told me
你祖父告诉我
for a long time now
很长一段时间以来
we've been able to do this.
我们已经能够做到这一点。
Dad.
爸爸。
That means, with this ability
这意味着，有了这种能力
-we can… -Can be rich?
—我们可以…—可以致富吗？
You can dream.
你可以做梦。
I've tried it. The money never sticks.
我试过了。钱永远粘不住。
Akid, listen here.
阿基德，听我说。
There are a few rules
有一些规则
that your great-grandfather followed,
你的曾祖父也曾这样做过，
your grandfather followed,
你的祖父也跟着来了，
and I followed.
我也跟着去了。
The first rule.
第一条规则。
When you go back in time to be rich
当你回到过去变得富有
it doesn't work.
它不起作用。
Is that true, Dad?
爸爸，这是真的吗？
I dabbled in stocks previously.
我以前涉足过股票。
Got a few hundred thousand in my account.
我的账户里有几十万。
I tasted it.
我尝了尝。
But when your grandfather got sick,
但当你祖父生病的时候，
it drained all the money I had.
它耗尽了我所有的钱。
It kept happening. Twice, thrice.
这种事一直发生，两次、三次。
The money, Akid, however you keep it
不管你怎样保管这笔钱，阿基德
won't stick.
不会粘住。
The second rule.
第二条规则。
Akid, look at this flower.
阿基德，看看这朵花。
This flower is destined to wither.
这朵花，注定要枯萎。
Whatever you do, it will still wither.
无论你做什么，它都会枯萎。
Sometimes, Akid,
有时，阿基德，
you have to accept
你必须接受
things that are destined to happen.
注定要发生的事情。
Understand?
理解？
Look at that grin.
看看那笑容。
Akid.
阿基德。
Akid, wake up.
阿基德，醒醒。
Dreaming of your girlfriend?
梦见你的女朋友了吗？
What, Mom?
什么，妈妈？
Gosh…
天哪……
Do you remember we said we’d go out today?
你还记得我们说过今天要出去吗？
Okay, hold on. I'll get ready.
好的，稍等一下。我去准备一下。
Feels like an Eid morning.
感觉就像开斋节的早晨。
This kid has just spoiled the moment.
这孩子真是把这一刻给毁了。
Mom, you're not ready. You said you'd come shopping with us.
妈妈，你还没准备好。你说过要和我们一起去购物的。
No, Mom is not coming along.
不，妈妈不跟来。
You woke up too late.
你醒得太晚了。
We're not going shopping after all.
我们毕竟不是去购物。
Come with me to buy fertilizer.
跟我一起去买肥料吧。
Look at the youngsters nowadays.
看看现在的年轻人。
They wake up late
他们起床晚了
and act all nonchalant.
并且表现得漠不关心。
No guilt at all. Let's go.
一点愧疚感都没有。走吧。
-I take my leave, Mom. -Okay.
—妈妈，我走了。—好的。
How much, Wong?
多少钱，黄？
One hundred and ten. But for you,
一百一十。但对你来说，
-just make it 100. -No.
—就设为 100。—不。
I inconvenienced you, take this 120.
给你添麻烦了，你收下这120吧。
Okay, thank you, sir.
好的，谢谢您，先生。
You look happy.
你看上去很开心。
Okay, it's settled.
好的，就这么定了。
Other shops have fertilizer too, Dad.
爸爸，其他商店也有肥料。
Why wait till night to buy gardening items?
为什么要等到晚上才购买园艺用品？
You won't understand. Only Wong's fertilizer will work
你不会明白的。只有黄的肥料才有效
on my flowers, you know that?
在我的花上，你知道吗？
What are you waiting for? That one.
还在等什么？就等那一个。
Let go of this bag!
放开这个包！
-I said, let it go! -Help!
—我说，放手吧！—救命！
-Or else!
—否则！—救命！
Hey!
嘿！
Dad!
爸爸！
Are you okay?
你还好嗎？
Dad.
爸爸。
Dad!
爸爸！
Akid!
阿基德！
The third rule,
第三条规则，
and it's the most important,
最重要的是，
you can only go back in time
你只能回到过去
when you are in a calm state.
当你处于平静状态时。
The person who stabbed him
刺伤他的人
was arrested yesterday.
昨天被捕。
Who is he, Mom? Where is he now?
妈妈，他是谁？他现在在哪里？
He's an addict, Akid.
他是个瘾君子，阿基德。
Don't waste your time.
别浪费你的时间。
And the car, that was an accident, Akid.
那辆车是一场事故，阿基德。
We have to accept
我们必须接受
that his time has come.
他的时机已经成熟。
This is fate, Akid.
这就是命运，阿基德。
We have to accept it.
我们必须接受它。
You have to be strong.
你必须坚强。
Promise me.
答应我。
You'll be strong.
你会变得坚强。
You have to be really strong.
你必须非常坚强。
Since that day,
从那天起，
I promised…
我答应了……
Sir.
先生。
to be stronger.
变得更强大。
POLICE INSPECTOR AKID AZIZ
警督阿基德·阿齐兹
Sir, over here.
先生，这边。
ELECTRIC MAINS
电源
Man.
男人。
Akid.
阿基德。
Her name is Aisyah, age 41.
她的名字叫艾莎，今年41岁。
Her daughter, Min, is in year six.
她的女儿敏今年六岁。
She's been in rehab for drug abuse.
她因吸毒而接受康复治疗。
She has stayed in this flat for about a year.
她已经在这个公寓里住了大约一年。
The whole place knows that she's a drug addict.
大家都知道她是个瘾君子。
You don't have to study it so much.
你不需要研究那么多。
Why not?
为什么不呢？
Isn't this open and shut for you?
这对你来说不是显而易见的吗？
Your record is perfect.
你的记录很完美。
I've never told anyone of this ability
我从未告诉过任何人这种能力
because I don't know
因为我不知道
what they would do
他们会做什么
if they had this ability.
如果他们有这个能力。
So I chose to keep it a secret.
所以我选择保守秘密。
Don't get close.
别靠近。
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Calm down.
冷静下来。
Calm down, Aisyah.
冷静下来，艾莎。
Aisyah, calm down.
艾莎，冷静点。
What do you want?
你想要什么？
That's Min, right?
那是 Min，对吗？
Aisyah.
艾莎。
Think about Min.
想想敏。
Poor Min.
可怜的敏。
Poor Min?
可怜的 Min？
All this while.
一直以来。
Has anyone cared about me? About Min?
有人关心过我吗？关心过敏吗？
No one here cares about me.
这里没有人关心我。
No one cares about Min.
没人关心 Min。
Aisyah.
艾莎。
If you jump, what would that solve?
如果你跳下去，能解决什么问题？
What would that solve?
这能解决什么问题？
If I jump.
如果我跳的话。
I will prove that I'm a good mom.
我会证明我是一个好妈妈。
Min.
分钟。
I love you.
我爱你。
I don't go back immediately when I fail.
当我失败时，我不会立即回头。
I try to appreciate my failure,
我尝试去欣赏我的失败，
and think about if I should change
并思考我是否应该改变
what is fated to be.
命中注定。
Why didn't you go back?
你为什么不回去？
Why didn't you go back to save me?
你为什么不回去救我？
You don't love me.
你不爱我。
I tried, I couldn't.
我尝试过，但是不行。
You're soft.
你很温柔。
All this time.
一直以来。
Have you cared about me? About Min?
你关心过我吗？关心过敏吗？
No one here cares about me.
这里没有人关心我。
No one cares about Min.
没人关心 Min。
Aisyah.
艾莎。
Listen to what I'm about to tell you.
听听我要告诉你的事。
I know.
我知道。
People belittle you.
人们贬低你。
Belittle Min.
轻视敏。
Because they don't understand you.
因为他们不理解你。
They don't feel your experiences.
他们感受不到你的经历。
But,
但，
have you ever asked Min
你有没有问过敏
if she wants all of this?
如果她想要这一切？
Min.
分钟。
Do you want all this?
你想要这一切吗？
If you die today
如果你今天死了
will all your problems go away?
你的所有问题都会消失吗？
Mom.
妈妈。
I want to live.
我想要活下去。
I want to live, I don't want to die.
我要活下去，我不想死。
Mom, I want to live.
妈妈，我想活下去。
I want to live, Mom. I don't want to die.
妈妈，我想活下去，我不想死。
This is my system.
这是我的系统。
The first number is the amount of attempts I've made to go back.
第一个数字是我尝试回去的次数。
The second number
第二个数字
is how long I want to go back.
是我想要回去多久。
ADRIANA'S OFFICE
阿德里亚娜的办公室
When I tick it
当我勾选它
that means my purpose for going back has been successful.
那就说明我回去的目的已经成功了。
But what is it for?
但它是用来做什么的呢？
Everytime I go back,
每次我回去，
I will be much older than before.
我会比以前老很多。
I have to sacrifice
我必须牺牲
my time in this world.
我在这个世界上的时间。
For example?
例如？
If I go back for a year
如果我回去一年
I will die a year earlier than my actual death date.
我将比实际死亡日期提前一年去世。
That means
这意味着
I would've sacrificed a year
我愿意牺牲一年
of my life.
我的生活。
But how would you know?
但你怎么知道呢？
I can feel it, Kabir.
我能感觉到，卡比尔。
My energy is not like before.
我的精力不像以前那么充沛了。
My body gets older
我的身体变老了
every time I go back.
每次我回去。
I began to realize that
我开始意识到
nothing is crueler than time.
没有什么比时间更残酷。
For time knows no patience.
因为时间没有耐心。
It will leave you in a flash.
它会瞬间离开你。
Because that's the nature of time.
因为这就是时间的本质。
It will take everything.
它将夺走一切。
Regardless of when
无论何时
and why.
以及原因。
Man.
男人。
You said we were going to dinner.
你说我们要去吃饭。
Why are we going to a party?
我们为什么要去参加聚会？
My friend invited us to this party.
我的朋友邀请我们参加这个聚会。
There's a barbecue.
有烧烤。
-Let's not. -Why?
—我们不要这样。—为什么？
Look at you.
看看你。
You don't want to socialize,
你不想社交，
don't want to chat to people.
不想和人聊天。
If you just stay at home, what do you get?
如果你只是呆在家里，你会得到什么？
Just cooped up.
只是被关起来了。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
There's mutton.
有羊肉。
Dude!
哥们！
There he goes, casually cutting the queue.
他就这样随意地插队了。
You just cut the queue, didn't even look back.
你直接插队了，甚至都没有回头。
Don't worry, there's plenty of mutton here.
别担心，这里有很多羊肉。
Listen to your friend.
听听你朋友的意见。
Misha.
米莎。
Akid, this is my friend, Misha.
Akid，这是我的朋友，Misha。
She's the one who invited us here.
是她邀请我们来这里的。
When did I invite you?
我什么时候邀请过你？
You were the one who begged to come.
是你恳求我来的。
Even if that's true
即使这是真的
don't say it in front of the mutton.
不要当着羊肉的面说这句话。
It's hurtful.
这很伤人。
Quickly.
迅速地。
-Hurry up! I'm hungry. -Hold on.
—快点！我饿了。—等一下。
I want the gizzard.
我想要砂囊。
But like I said,
但就像我说的，
the nature of time is to take.
时间的本质就是消耗。
But time also gives.
但时间也会给予。
For no reason,
毫无理由地，
time gave me Sarah.
时间给了我莎拉。
-Hold on, I'm looking for the wing. -It's this one.
—等一下，我在找机翼。—就是这个。
-Hi! -Sarah.
—嗨！—莎拉。
Why didn't you pick me up? See, I'm late.
你为什么不来接我？你看，我迟到了。
Sorry, I had to be here early.
抱歉，我必须早点到这里。
The mutton is here.
羊肉来了。
What are you looking at?
你在看什麼？
Sorry.
对不起。
-You stare at girls and daydream. -I'm not.
—你盯着女孩做白日梦。—我没有。
Sarah.
莎拉。
Luq-man.
路加福音。
Akid.
阿基德。
Sarah.
莎拉。
Luqman, let's have a burger inside.
鲁格曼，我们进去吃个汉堡吧。
-There are burgers inside? -Yes.
—里面有汉堡吗？—有。
-Let's move. -Let's go.
—我们走吧。—我们走吧。
Told me what many times?
跟我说过多少次了？
So focused.
非常专注。
No.
不。
Just watching them about to fight.
只是看着他们即将打架。
You don't seem to be into parties.
你似乎不喜欢参加聚会。
No, I'm just always busy.
不，我只是一直很忙。
No time for parties.
没有时间参加聚会。
Especially when you get this kind of view.
尤其是当你看到这种观点时。
You're so funny.
你真有趣。
-Really? -Yes.
—真的吗？—是的。
Okay, that means I should change my career to be a stand-up comedian.
好吧，这意味着我应该转行成为一名单口喜剧演员。
What do you do now?
你现在做什么？
Okay, I will be going now.
好的，我现在就走。
Wait, why?
等等，为什么？
Nothing.
没有什么。
Do I give off crook vibes?
我是不是给人一种骗子的感觉？
-You got me. -I'm just kidding.
-你懂我的意思。-我只是在开玩笑。
No wonder I couldn't find you,
难怪我找不到你，
you're here.
你在这里。
Do you know that you're currently socializing with a hero.
你知道你目前正在与一位英雄交往吗？
There's no need, Man.
没有必要，伙计。
Hero?
英雄？
Yes.
是的。
Do you know this guy just saved a woman from
你知道这家伙刚刚救了一个女人吗？
jumping off a building with her daughter.
和女儿一起跳楼。
Saved?
已儲存？
What's up?
这是怎么回事？
I have work tomorrow. Let's go home.
明天还要上班，我们回家吧。
Sarah, in a while?
莎拉，一会儿吧？
It's still early. I want to hang out here.
时间还早，想在这里逛逛。
You promised to take me home. Let's go.
你答应过要带我回家的。走吧。
In a while, Sarah.
一会儿，莎拉。
In a while. Misha wants to hang with me.
一会儿吧。米莎想和我一起玩。
Akid doesn’t want to stay.
Akid 不想留下来。
He can take you home.
他可以带你回家。
Right, Akid? You can take her back, right?
对吧，阿基德？你可以把她带回去，对吧？
Sorry, my car…
抱歉，我的车……
is a bit messy.
有点乱。
If…
如果…
you could go back in time.
你可以回到过去。
Go back in time? What?
回到过去？什么？
No, I was just thinking.
不，我只是在思考。
If you could go back in time,
如果可以回到过去，
are there many things you'd want to fix?
有很多事情你想修复吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Not sure.
没有把握。
What about you?
你呢？
Maybe one or two things.
也许有一两件事。
But I appreciate my mistakes.
但我承认我犯了错误。
The mistakes I made in the past
我过去犯的错误
shaped me to be who I am now.
塑造了现在的我。
But don't tell me you don’t have
但别告诉我你没有
things you really regret doing.
你确实后悔做过的事情。
It's like this.
是這樣的。
I don't want to be afraid of the future,
我不想害怕未来，
and I don't regret my past.
我并不后悔我的过去。
I want to live for the moment.
我想要活在当下。
Tomorrow
明天
I have an Aikido demonstration.
我有一个合气道表演。
Aikido?
合气道？
If you're free, come.
如果你有空，就来吧。
Everyone will agree that
每个人都会同意
usually these feelings
通常这些感觉
can't be explained with logic and reason.
无法用逻辑和理性来解释。
Because I feel like my body moved on it's own
因为我感觉我的身体自己动了
to come here.
来到这里。
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome.
女士们、先生们，早上好！欢迎大家光临。
Today, we'll start the program
今天，我们将启动该计划
with a martial arts demonstration
武术表演
that will be performed by Sensei Sarah Zulkifli.
由 Sarah Zulkifli 老师表演。
No problem.
没问题。
You fought amazingly.
你打得非常出色。
You don't want to become a police officer?
你不想成为一名警察吗？
-You don't? -No.
—你不知道吗？—不知道。
But I saw you spinning them around,
但我看到你旋转着它们，
dropping them all over the place.
把它们扔得到处都是。
When you first started learning, it must've be the same.
当你刚开始学习的时候，情况一定是一样的。
To fall so many times.
跌倒了这么多次。
Did it hurt?
疼吗？
It did hurt a little bit.
确实有点疼。
But if we don't feel the pain,
但如果我们没有感受到痛苦，
how will we get stronger, right?
我们怎样才能变得更强大呢？
Do you like MMA?
你喜欢 MMA 吗？
Looking sharp to meet your girlfriend?
期待与你的女朋友见面吗？
Why haven't you eaten?
你怎么还没吃饭？
I have something to talk to you about.
我有事要和你谈。
What is it?
它是什么？
Why don't you eat first?
你为什么不先吃饭呢？
Actually.
实际上。
Actually,
实际上，
I met someone.
我遇见了一个人。
Her name is Sarah.
她的名字叫莎拉。
I've known her for two years.
我认识她两年了。
She teaches Japanese martial arts, Aikido.
她教授日本武术合气道。
She's special, Mom.
妈妈，她很特别。
Are you really serious about this?
你是认真的吗？
Things like this shouldn't be taken lightly.
诸如此类的事情不应该被轻视。
After Dad died,
爸爸去世后，
I don't know why,
我不知道为什么，
it's so hard for me to get rid of my sadness.
我很难摆脱悲伤。
I know I have to be strong.
我知道我必须坚强。
Strong for myself, strong for you.
为自己坚强，为你坚强。
But,
但，
meeting Sarah
遇见莎拉
has made me appreciate life even more.
让我更加珍惜生命。
Sarah has become the purpose of my life.
莎拉已经成为我生活的目标。
To the point
说到点子上
where I can forget everything
在那里我可以忘记一切
that I struggled to forget.
我努力去忘记。
That's why I feel I am ready, Mom.
这就是为什么我觉得我已经准备好了，妈妈。
I'm ready to marry Sarah.
我已准备好与莎拉结婚。
-What did she give you? -Nothing.
—她给了你什么？—什么也没有。
What did you want to say?
你想说什么？
Interested?
感兴趣的？
Too early?
太早了？
I thought two years of knowing each other
我以为认识两年
was enough.
就足够了。
No.
不。
It's enough.
够了。
I need a little time.
我需要一点时间。
Yeah, things like this can't be rushed.
是啊，这种事不能操之过急。
You have to think carefully.
你必须仔细考虑一下。
It's okay, take your time.
没关系，慢慢来。
Akid.
阿基德。
Sarah.
莎拉。
It's raining.
下雨了。
Yes, except what?
是的，除了什么？
I will marry you.
我会娶你。
So dramatic, in the rain.
雨中，如此戏剧化。
Water dripping in my eyes.
水滴进我的眼睛。
Since you've accepted,
既然你已经接受了，
I have something to tell you.
我有事要告诉你。
How do you know what's in my handbag?
你怎么知道我的手提包里有什么？
How do you know the number I'm thinking of?
你怎么知道我想的数字？
Sarah. Sarah, it hurts.
莎拉。莎拉，好痛。
My shoulders are going to pop, Sarah.
我的肩膀要爆裂了，莎拉。
Explain to me how do you suddenly have magic powers.
向我解释一下你是怎么突然拥有魔力的。
What magic?
什么魔法？
I can time travel.
我可以穿越时空。
Okay, I'll admit that initially
好吧，我承认一开始
I didn't want to tell you at all,
我根本就不想告诉你，
and let this be my secret forever.
并让这永远成为我的秘密。
But you're different, Sarah.
但你与众不同，莎拉。
When you accepted,
当你接受的时候，
that's when I thought you should know everything about me.
那时我就​​觉得你应该了解我的一切。
You can go back in time.
你可以回到过去。
You can fix anything you want, right?
您可以修复任何您想要修复的东西，对吗？
So have you ever
那么你有没有
gone back in time
回到过去
to make sure you say the right thing to me.
确保你对我说了正确的话。
To make sure you say things that I want to hear. Have you?
确保你说的是我想听的话。是吗？
Remember that time in the car?
还记得在车里的那次吗？
You said something to me.
你对我说了些什么。
You said
你说
you don't want to be afraid of the future.
你不想害怕未来。
You don't want to regret the past.
你不想对过去感到后悔。
You want to live for the moment.
你想活在当下。
I want to live for the moment.
我想要活在当下。
It can't be that easy to time travel.
时间旅行并不是那么容易的。
Are there no consequences?
沒有後果嗎？
Yes.
是的。
There are.
有。
If…
如果…
I do it a lot, I will get older faster.
我做得越多，我就会老得越快。
Old, like how?
老了，怎么样？
White hairs.
白发。
You promise me.
你答应我。
You won't use this ability anymore.
你将不再使用这个能力。
Because I want to die before you.
因为我想先你而死。
Because I don't need for you to have superpowers
因为我不需要你有超能力
or magic powers.
或魔力。
I don't want to live if you're not around, Akid.
如果没有你，我就不想活了，阿基德。
Okay, I promise.
好的，我保证。
Peace be upon you.
愿你平安。
-Mom. -Peace be upon you.
—妈妈。—愿您安息。
Are you okay in the kitchen?
你在厨房还好吗？
Do you need help?
你需要幫助嗎？
He's afraid I will talk badly about him.
他害怕我会说他的坏话。
You've accepted, right?
你已经接受了，对吗？
You're serious about Akid?
你对 Akid 是认真的吗？
Yes, Aunty.
是的，阿姨。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Akid is like his father.
阿基德就像他的父亲。
Good,
好的，
but stubborn.
但很固执。
And sometimes,
有时，
they will try
他们会尝试
to give more than what we want
给予比我们想要的更多
even though we never asked.
尽管我们从未问过。
What do you like about Akid?
您喜欢 Akid 的哪些方面？
I like him because
我喜欢他因为
he's cute.
他很可爱。
Peace be upon you, please come in.
愿您平安，请进来。
Thank you for coming.
谢谢您的到来。
Peace be upon you, sir.
祝您安息，先生。
Thank you, please come in.
谢谢，请进。
At last, the happiest day of my life had come.
我一生中最幸福的一天终于到来了。
It felt like
感觉就像
time had stopped.
时间已经停止了。
In this world,
在这个世界上，
it seems like there is only me and Sarah.
好像只有我和莎拉。
Akid bin Abdul Aziz,
阿基德·本·阿卜杜勒·阿齐兹，
I marry you to Sarah Binti Zulkifli
我把你嫁给莎拉·宾蒂·祖基菲里
with the dowry of RM250 cash.
嫁妆为 RM250 现金。
Mr Akid.,
阿基德先生，
I accept the marriage
我接受这桩婚事
to Sarah Binti Zulkifli
致 Sarah Binti Zulkifli
with the dowry of RM250 cash.
嫁妆为 RM250 现金。
Sometimes, don't you feel it's strange
有时候，你不觉得很奇怪吗
how people can be?
人怎能如此？
Because I believe
因为我相信
everyone has experienced this.
每个人都经历过这种情况。
You wake up, sleep, eat, drink, work,
你醒来、睡觉、吃饭、喝水、工作，
but you feel empty.
但你却感觉空虚。
What do you mean by empty?
你说的空是什么意思？
Like life has no value.
就像生命没有价值一样。
Because when I work every day
因为当我每天工作的时候
that empty feeling
那种空虚的感觉
will haunt me,
会困扰我，
and I'm sure that
我确信
everyone must have experienced that feeling too.
大家肯定也经历过这种感觉。
But Sarah…
但是莎拉……
Sarah made all the ordinary things
莎拉制作了所有普通的东西
feel even more worthwhile.
感觉更加值得。
Because no matter what,
因为无论怎样，
I still had to go on being a cop.
我还是得继续当警察。
Sarah was also busy with her students.
莎拉也忙着照顾她的学生。
But we would never forget
但我们永远不会忘记
to spend time together.
一起度过时光。
Even simple things like watching TV,
即使是像看电视这样简单的事情，
and chatting together.
并一起聊天。
We always had things to talk about.
我们总是有话要谈。
Ordinary things like dining together.
一起吃饭之类的普通事。
Before I knew it,
在我还没意识到之前，
after Sarah came into my life,
自从莎拉进入我的生活后，
I had no interest in going back.
我对回去没有兴趣。
I promised myself
我向自己保证
not to use this ability anymore.
不再使用此功能。
I just wanted to make sure
我只是想确认一下
that I appreciated every moment with Sarah.
我珍惜与莎拉在一起的每一刻。
Until
直到
I made the biggest mistake
我犯了最大的错误
of my life.
我的生活。
Akid.
阿基德。
Sorry for intruding on your leave.
很抱歉打扰了您的休假。
How's Sarah?
莎拉怎么样了？
No ID
无身份证
I think he's a first-timer.
我认为他是第一次来。
But he's had the hostages for six hours.
但他已经劫持人质六个小时了。
We've tried talking to him, Akid.
我们尝试和他交谈，阿基德。
But he refused.
但他拒绝了。
Sir,
先生，
I'm a police officer.
我是一名警察。
I'm coming in.
我进来了。
Sir.
先生。
I'm a cop, I'm unarmed.
我是一名警察，我没有携带武器。
I'm coming in, sir.
我进来了，先生。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
-No, I'm coming in. -Get out!
—不，我要进来。—出去！
No, please calm down, sir.
不，先生，请冷静一下。
I said, get out!
我说，出去！
Sir.
先生。
I'm not armed. I'm alone, sir
我没有武器。我一个人，先生
I said, get out!
我说，出去！
-Sir. -Get out!
—先生。—出去！
Sir, calm down.
先生，请冷静一下。
My name is Akid.
我的名字是 Akid。
I'm a cop. I won't do anything to you.
我是警察，我不会对你做什么。
I just want to speak to you.
我只是想和你谈谈。
I don't care who you are.
我不在乎你是谁。
I said, out. Get out!
我说，出去。出去！
Calm down, sir.
冷静一下，先生。
Calm down.
冷静下来。
Sorry ma'am, we can't wait anymore.
抱歉，女士，我们不能再等了。
We have to go in now.
我们现在必须进去。
Sir, calm down.
先生，请冷静一下。
Just focus on me.
只关注我。
I know you have problems now.
我知道你现在有问题。
I know you don't really want to do this.
我知道你其实不想这么做。
You don't get it.
你不明白。
You have children?
你有孩子吗？
Not yet.
还没有。
You won't understand what it feels like
你不会明白那是什么感觉
to hear your child beg and cry.
听到你的孩子乞求和哭泣。
Why? Because he's hungry
为什么？因为他饿了
and I was fired,
我被解雇了，
and now they want me out of my house.
现在他们想让我搬出去。
Sarah, relax. Exhale.
莎拉，放松。呼气。
I'm not smart.
我不聪明。
I'm not successful.
我没有成功。
My wife died giving birth to my son.
我的妻子在生我儿子时去世了。
Doctor, the baby's heartbeat has dropped significantly.
医生，宝宝的心跳明显下降了。
Do we need to proceed with a cesarean section?
我们需要进行剖腹产吗？
It's okay, let's try again.
没关系，我们再试一次。
I raised my child.
我养育了我的孩子。
I raised him alone.
我独自抚养他长大。
And now they want to take him away.
现在他们想把他带走。
-They? -Yes!
—他们？—是的！
You people!
你们这些人！
Who say I cannot afford to raise my child.
谁说我没有能力抚养我的孩子。
All this while, I've lived for him.
一直以来，我都为他而活。
I do all this for him.
我做这一切都是为了他。
I've been evicted from my house.
我被赶出了家。
How am I going to pay rent?
我该如何支付房租？
Do you think I do all this just for fun?
你以为我做这一切只是为了好玩吗？
Sarah, wake up.
莎拉，醒醒。
Push harder, I can see the head now, come.
用力推，我现在可以看到头了，来吧。
A bit more.
再多一点。
Sarah!
莎拉！
Sarah is in a critical condition.
莎拉的情况危急。
Sir, it's like this.
先生，事情是这样的。
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
I know.
我知道。
It's not a lot,
不算多，
but maybe it can help you with the rent.
但也许它可以帮助你支付房租。
My wife is at the hospital
我的妻子在医院
giving birth to our first child.
生下我们的第一个孩子。
I don't know what you're fighting for,
我不知道你为何而战，
but maybe in time I will know.
但也许随着时间的推移我就会知道。
This is what I can help you with.
这就是我能帮到您的。
BAN SOON TRADING COMPANY AND DRUG STORE
班顺贸易公司和药店
-Check on the hostage. -Akid, what's going on?
—检查人质情况。—阿基德，发生什么事了？
-He ran but the hostage is safe. -I'm out of time.
—他跑了，但人质安全了。—我没时间了。
The hostage is safe, but you're running.
人质安全了，但你却在逃跑。
Sarah Zulkifli's ward.
莎拉·祖尔基夫利 (Sarah Zulkifli) 的病房。
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
-Jati Ward. -Jati Ward, thank you.
—Jati Ward。—Jati Ward，谢谢你。
Darling.
亲爱的。
It's okay, I understand.
没关系，我明白。
How is it? Is your work settled?
怎么样？工作安顿好了吗？
Look at you.
看看你。
You don't have to worry.
你不必担心。
And you, are you okay?
你还好吗？
I'm a fighter, remember?
我是一名战士，记得吗？
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
以至仁至慈的真主之名。
Peace be upon you.
愿你平安。
You want to meet Mommy?
你想见妈妈吗？
Want to meet Mommy?
想见妈妈吗？
He's opening his eyes, dear.
亲爱的，他正在睁开眼睛。
-Look. -Hi.
—看。—嗨。
He's yawning.
他在打哈欠。
Peace be upon you.
愿你平安。
Congratulations, ma'am, sir.
恭喜您，女士，先生。
-Thank you. -Sorry to bother you.
—谢谢。—抱歉打扰您。
What is it, Doctor?
怎么了，医生？
Okay, I want to ask about your family's medical history.
好的，我想问一下你家人的病史。
Anyone with hemophilia?
有血友病患者吗？
A condition in which blood clots slowly.
血液凝结缓慢的状况。
My grandmother.
我的祖母。
Fate is not unkind.
命运并不冷酷。
We just never know its blessings.
我们只是永远不知道它的益处。
Sarah.
莎拉。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I'm confident everything will be okay.
我相信一切都会好起来的。
I will be with you.
我会和你在一起。
I will be with Anas.
我会和阿纳斯在一起。
This made me remember.
这让我记忆犹新。
Dad.
爸爸。
What are you looking at?
你在看什麼？
Let's go home, Tauke Wong is about to close.
我们回家吧，Tauke Wong 快要关门了。
When I look at the neem tree, I remember
当我看到印度楝树时，我想起
when you had measles.
当你患麻疹时。
I had measles?
我得了麻疹吗？
You don't even remember.
你甚至都不记得了。
Remember this.
记住这一点。
When you're married with children,
当你结婚生子时，
responsibility is not just for worldly matters.
责任不仅仅针对世俗事务。
You have to give everything.
你必须付出一切。
You live for your children, remember that.
你为你的孩子而活，记住这一点。
Maybe because, deep down, I knew
也许是因为，在内心深处，我知道
I was afraid that
我担心
I couldn't be a good dad like my dad.
我无法像我爸爸一样成为一个好爸爸。
But
但
I could still try my best.
我还可以尽力。
The most important thing
最重要的事情
was to be happy.
是幸福的。
But in a flash,
但转眼间，
time passes when we're happy.
当我们快乐的时候，时间就过去了。
You.
你。
Talk to him.
和他谈谈。
Nas.
在。
How many times have I told you not to drink sweet drinks?
我告诉过你多少次不要喝甜饮料？
This is only a little.
这只是一点点。
No, it's not a little, it's a lot.
不，不是一点点，而是很多。
Look.
看。
I told you not to fold your sleeves.
我告诉过你不要卷袖子。
Enough.
足够的。
-He's annoyed at us? -Let's go.
—他对我们生气了？—我们走吧。
-Dad, do you know what day it is today?
—我们走吧。—爸爸，你知道今天是什么日子吗？
Of course I know.
我当然知道。
I wouldn't forget.
我不会忘记。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Quickly, make a wish.
快快许愿吧。
I wish that Mom wouldn't nag me anymore.
我希望妈妈不要再唠叨我了。
It's not nice to make a wish like that.
许这样的愿望并不好。
-Wish properly. -Okay.
—好好许愿。—好的。
I wish that you and Dad will always
我希望你和爸爸永远
be around for my birthdays until I'm old.
陪我过生日直到我老去。
Get real, just say you want an iPad.
说实话，就说你想要一台 iPad。
I want that too.
我也想要那个。
Have we
我们是否
ever felt sad
曾经感到悲伤
when we are happy
当我们快乐的时候
because we're afraid
因为我们害怕
we will be sad
我们会伤心
when that happiness is gone?
幸福什么时候消失了？
Because after that
因为在那之后
my life was destroyed.
我的生活被毁了。
-It's raining. Still want to go out? -Yes.
—下雨了。还想出去吗？—是的。
This kid.
这小子。
Huh?
咦？
What's wrong, Mom?
妈妈，怎么了？
I don't know.
我不知道。
NATIONAL POLICE STATION
国家警察局
Your dad never picks up the phone.
你爸爸从来不接电话。
-Want to take a FlyCar? -Yes.
-想乘坐 FlyCar 吗？-是的。
Okay, take off your seatbelt.
好的，解开你的安全带。
Wait for me, don't go out first.
等我一下，你别先出去。
Anas.
阿纳斯。
Okay, get in.
好的，进来吧。
Be careful.
当心。
Anas.
阿纳斯。
I told you not to fold your sleeves.
我告诉过你不要卷袖子。
I don't want you to fall and hurt yourself.
我不想让你摔倒并受伤。
Come, Anas.
来吧，阿纳斯。
Thank you, sir.
谢谢您，先生。
Wait, Anas.
等一下，阿纳斯。
Not too fast, you'll get soaked.
不要太快，你会被淋湿的。
Home would be so good right now.
现在的家真是太好了。
Okay, let's go.
好的，我们走吧。
Anas.
阿纳斯。
At the time, I realized
当时我意识到
a strange thing.
一件奇怪的事情。
I wasn't haunted by sadness.
我并没有被悲伤所困扰。
I was just
我只是
angry
生气的
because I knew
因为我知道
I could change this.
我可以改变这一点。
In this world,
在这个世界上，
only I was able to.
只有我能做到。
You.
你。
Now I've been kicked out of the house!
现在我被赶出家门了！
After all that I've done.
在我做完这一切之后。
This is how you repay me?
这就是你报答我的方式？
I regret helping you.
我很遗憾帮助你。
What time? Where?
几点？在哪里？
I am asking you, what time? Where?
我问你，几点？哪里？
What time did you kill my wife and child?
你什么时候杀了我的妻儿？
What time? What time?
几点？几点？
This time, I won't make
这次，我不会
the same mistake.
同样的错误。
This time I know
这次我知道了
I can go back.
我可以回去。
Because in this world,
因为在这个世界上，
only I can beat time.
只有我能战胜时间。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
I'm going to buy Lego.
我要去买乐高。
Lego? We just bought Lego last week.
乐高？我们上周刚买了乐高。
I want more.
我想要更多。
Okay, we'll ask Dad to buy some. Okay?
好的，我们让爸爸买一些。可以吗？
Sarah.
莎拉。
Anas, don't cross the road.
阿纳斯，不要过马路。
Sarah!
莎拉！
NATIONAL POLICE DEPARTMENT PEACEFUL, FAIR, EFFICIENT
国家警察部门和平、公正、高效
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Sarah.
莎拉。
This flower is destined to wither.
这朵花，注定要枯萎。
Whatever you do, it will still wither.
无论你做什么，它都会枯萎。
Sometimes, Akid,
有时，阿基德，
you have to accept things that are destined to happen.
你必须接受注定要发生的事情。
Akid.
阿基德。
Try to make me understand.
尝试让我明白。
Why don’t you go back to one or two days earlier?
为什么不早一两天回去呢？
-You studied what I told you to yesterday? -Yes.
—你学习了我昨天告诉你的内容吗？—是的。
All of it?
全部？
Okay, you're going to get an A?
好的，你会得到 A 吗？
All right.
好的。
Sarah.
莎拉。
You don't have to send Anas today.
你今天不必派阿纳斯去。
Anas, no need to go to school, okay?
阿纳斯，不用去上学了，好吗？
Why?
为什么？
No, today nobody goes out.
不，今天没人出门。
He has an exam today.
他今天有考试。
Let's go, Anas.
走吧，阿纳斯。
Later you help to clean up, okay?
待会儿你帮忙打扫一下好吗？
Sarah, wait. Anas.
莎拉，等一下。阿纳斯。
Please.
请。
Don’t go out of the house today, please.
今天请不要出门。
Why are you acting so strange today?
你今天的行为为何这么奇怪？
Wait here, I'm going to the toilet.
你在这里等着，我去趟厕所。
Wait a moment.
稍等。
Anas, darling.
阿纳斯，亲爱的。
You go inside.
你进去吧。
Go play, do whatever you want.
去玩吧，做任何你想做的事。
School is canceled today.
今天学校停课。
Sarah.
莎拉。
No, no.
不不不。
Don't, Sarah.
别这样，莎拉。
Sarah, no.
莎拉，不。
No.
不。
Anas.
阿纳斯。
Darling.
亲爱的。
Your exam is tomorrow, right?
你的考试是明天，对吗？
I've circled it in your book.
我已在你的书中圈出了它。
-You just have to read it. -Okay.
—你只需要读它。—好的。
Promise to be a good boy and get all As.
保证做一个好孩子并取得全A。
Don't you want your cake?
你不想要你的蛋糕吗？
Do you want anything to eat?
你想吃点什么吗？
Noodles? I'll make it for you.
面条？我给你做。
Mom, I want nuggets.
妈妈，我想要鸡块。
No, there's fried chicken there.
不，那里有炸鸡。
-Mom, I want nuggets. -No.
—妈妈，我想要鸡块。—不。
There's fried chicken, there's cake. Why do you want nuggets?
有炸鸡，有蛋糕，干嘛还要鸡块？
I want nuggets!
我想要金块！
No, Anas. I said no.
不，阿纳斯。我说了不。
But I want nuggets!
但我想要金块！
Anas don't play with that gas.
阿纳斯 (Anas) 不要玩弄那种气体。
It's dangerous.
这很危险。
I want nuggets.
我想要金块。
Don't play with the gas.
别玩煤气。
It's dangerous.
这很危险。
Anas, don't touch it. It's dangerous.
阿纳斯，别碰它。它很危险。
Anas.
阿纳斯。
Anas, are you okay?
阿纳斯，你还好吗？
Anything?
任何事物？
Anas.
阿纳斯。
-Anas! -Sir!
—阿纳斯！—先生！
-Sarah, what happened? -Baby! I don't know!
-莎拉，发生什么事了？-宝贝！我不知道！
-I don't know! -Anas!
—我不知道！—阿纳斯！
What's this?
这是什么？
That's enough!
够了！
Sir? Sir!
先生？先生！
-Sir, please open the door. -Oh, God!
—先生，请开门。—哦，天哪！
Sarah.
莎拉。
-I tried. -Where are my car keys?
-我试过了。-我的车钥匙在哪里？
The keys…
钥匙……
Whatever I could,
无论我怎样努力，
I tried,
我试过，
Why, sir?
为什么，先生？
-Sir? -Anas!
—先生？—阿纳斯！
and tried,
并尝试过，
and tried.
并尝试过。
The more I tried,
我越努力，
the less logical it became.
它变得越不合逻辑。
But I kept on trying.
但我还是继续努力。
But after a while,
但过了一段时间，
I understood.
我明白了。
The more I went back,
我越回去，
the worse their deaths became.
他们的死亡情况就越糟糕。
Why didn't you stop Hisham
你为什么不阻止 Hisham
from driving that day? Maybe you could--
那天开车的时候？也许你可以——
Don't you understand what I'm saying?
你不明白我在说什么吗？
I have tried everything.
我已经尝试了一切。
I…
我…
When I go back,
当我回去的时候，
I have to go through it
我必须经历这一切
all over again,
再一次，
and I cannot change anything.
而我却无法改变任何事情。
Why?
为什么？
Because I realized I could only
因为我意识到我只能
save them at that exact moment.
在那一刻拯救他们。
Only at the moment of the accident.
只在事故发生的那一刻。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Akid.
阿基德。
Aren't you tired?
你不累吗？
When you are determined
当你下定决心
to fight fate,
与命运抗争，
you cease to be human.
你不再是人了。
At that time I became obsessed.
那时我就​​着迷了。
I couldn't give up.
我不能放弃。
Akid.
阿基德。
What is this?
这是什么？
TUN ISMAIL TOWER
敦伊斯梅尔塔
Whatever happened,
无论发生什么，
I would win.
我会赢。
SEVEN HOURS AND FIFTY-FOUR MINUTES EIGHT HOURS
七小时五十四分钟 八小时
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Akid.
阿基德。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
After hundreds of attempts,
经过数百次尝试，
Akid.
阿基德。
hundreds of failures.
数百次失败。
But I've researched,
但我研究过，
I've memorized, I've repeated.
我已经记住了，我已经重复了。
Hundreds of times.
数百次。
Hey! That's my motorcyle!
嘿！那是我的摩托车！
Nineteenth Street, Kerinchi.
克林奇第十九街。
Hurry.
匆忙。
Those hundreds of attempts
数百次尝试
in about…
大约…
more than a year.
一年多了。
But in the end,
但最终，
I had the answer
我有答案
to my struggle.
为我的奋斗。
After the traffic light, just stop.
过了红绿灯，就停下来。
After the traffic light, stop.
过了交通灯，就停车。
Stop.
停止。
I can only pick one.
我只能选一个。
Sarah!
莎拉！
Even though I was able to save Sarah,
尽管我救了莎拉，
the Sarah I saved
我拯救的莎拉
wasn't the same Sarah.
不再是同一个莎拉了。
Why didn't you save Anas?
你为什么不救阿纳斯？
Honestly, I was afraid
说实话，我很害怕
that if I tried another time,
如果我再试一次，
I would lose Sarah again.
我会再次失去莎拉。
Why didn't you save Anas?
你为什么不救阿纳斯？
Why didn't you go back?
你为什么不回去？
Why didn't you go back and save Anas?
你为什么不回去救阿纳斯？
I told you.
我告诉你了。
I won't go back.
我不会回去。
Why are you lying?
你为什么撒谎？
Hundreds of times, Sarah.
数百次，莎拉。
I went back hundreds of times.
我回去过数百次。
Maybe if I go back again,
也许如果我再回去，
-you wouldn't be here. -You shouldn't have saved me!
—你不会在这里。—你不应该救我！
You remember this?
你还记得这个吗？
What's this, Datin?
这是什么，达汀？
Sarah, since my son joined your class
莎拉，自从我儿子加入你的班以来
his social anxiety has lessened.
他的社交焦虑减轻了。
But, unfortunately,
但不幸的是，
my husband is transferring to Sabah.
我的丈夫正在调往沙巴。
My husband and I noticed.
我和我丈夫注意到了。
Aikido has helped my son immensely.
合气道对我儿子的帮助非常大。
Please coach my son in Sabah.
请在沙巴指导我的儿子。
I need a little more time.
我需要多一点时间。
I have personal reasons, Datin.
我有个人原因，Datin。
Yes, Datin.
是的，女士。
What's your point, exactly?
你到底想表达什么意思？
I should have
我应该
accepted the offer to go to Sabah.
接受了前往沙巴的邀请。
If I had accepted it,
如果我接受了，
I wouldn't be hurt like this.
我不会被这样伤害。
Akid!
阿基德！
You have to go back.
你必须回去。
Whatever happens.
无论发生什么。
You have to go back!
你必须回去！
You hear me?
你听见了吗？
You have to go back, Akid!
你必须回去，阿基德！
Akid!
阿基德！
You have to go back!
你必须回去！
I don't want to be afraid of my future.
我不想害怕我的未来。
And I don't want to regret the past.
我不想对过去感到后悔。
I want to live for the moment.
我想要活在当下。
Akid, go back!
阿基德，回去吧！
Go back! You have to go back!
回去！你必须回去！
Akid!
阿基德！
You have to go back, understand?
你必须回去，明白吗？
Understand?
理解？
I managed to save Anas,
我成功救下了阿纳斯，
but…
但…
Dad, where's Mom?
爸爸，妈妈呢？
Dad, where's Mom? I want Mom.
爸爸，妈妈呢？我要妈妈。
Dad, I want Mom.
爸爸，我想要妈妈。
Look at this.
看看这个。
This is Mom, right? Look at this.
这是妈妈吧？看看这个。
Look at all of this.
看看这一切。
Look at it, Anas. Look.
看吧，阿纳斯。看吧。
Look as much as you want!
想看多少就看多少！
Mom is gone!
妈妈走了！
Mom is no longer with us.
妈妈已经不在我们身边了。
Mom won't be back.
妈妈不会回来了。
Listen here. I'm going to say it one more time!
听着，我再说一遍！
Where's Mom? Where's Mom? I don't want to hear it anymore!
妈妈呢？妈妈呢？我不想再听了！
You understand?
你明白吗？
I don't want to hear anymore!
我不想再听了！
Enough! Enough!
够了！够了！
Anas.
阿纳斯。
After that, my relationship with Anas fell apart.
从那以后，我和阿纳斯的关系破裂了。
Without Sarah, I didn't know…
如果没有莎拉，我不知道……
Eat your medicine first.
先吃药吧。
how to be a good dad.
如何成为一名好爸爸。
Finish your medicine first.
先把药吃完吧。
Without Sarah,
如果没有莎拉，
I became a failure.
我失败了。
The same thing happened after I saved Sarah.
在我救了莎拉之后也发生了同样的事情。
Anas
阿纳斯
was not the same.
不一样。
He was a stranger.
他是一个陌生人。
But this time, everything was caused by me.
但这一次，一切都是我造成的。
Sometimes,
有时，
I feel
我觉得
the ability that I have
我的能力
is not a gift.
不是礼物。
It's more like a curse.
这更像是一种诅咒。
So,
所以，
after that…
在那之后…
-Akid. -Mom.
—阿基德。—妈妈。
Why didn't you tell me you were coming?
你为什么不告诉我你要来？
Grandma.
奶奶。
Anas.
阿纳斯。
I thought I'd take Anas out today.
我想今天带阿纳斯出去。
Just to hang out.
只是出去玩。
Why didn't you ask me first, Mom?
妈妈，你为什么不先问我呢？
It might be risky.
这可能有风险。
Go and get ready.
去准备一下吧。
What's wrong with you?
你这人怎么回事？
Why?
为什么？
You know that Anas has hemophilia.
你知道阿纳斯患有血友病。
What if something happens?
如果发生什么事怎么办？
What then?
那么接下来呢？
You want to lock him up forever?
你想把他永远关起来吗？
You can't do this to your son.
你不能这样对你的儿子。
It's a form of abuse.
这是一种虐待。
Akid.
阿基德。
What happened is not your fault.
所发生的事不是你的错。
We can't control everything.
我们无法控制一切。
Don't turn Anas into a victim.
不要让阿纳斯成为受害者。
Grandma.
奶奶。
Let's go, we're late.
走吧，我们迟到了。
Yes, let's go.
是的，我们走吧。
Akid,
阿基德，
the past is gone.
过去的已经过去了。
Let go of it.
放手吧。
Sir, ma'am.
先生，女士。
We are trying to stabilize your son.
我们正在努力稳定你儿子的病情。
He has lost a lot of blood.
他失血过多。
His blood type is O negative.
他的血型是O型阴性。
We're waiting for the blood supply to come
我们正在等待血液供应
to do a transfusion.
去做输血。
Don't Akid.
别阿基德。
Flowers will wither, Akid.
花儿会枯萎，阿基德。
You still remember?
你還記得嗎？
You know?
你知道？
You and your dad
你和你的爸爸
are the same,
都是一样的，
stubborn.
固执的。
I have told him
我已经告诉过他了
not to.
不。
Things like this shouldn't happen.
这种事情不应该发生。
He told me.
他告诉我的。
Feels like an Eid morning.
感觉就像开斋节的早晨。
Help!
帮助！
Hey!
嘿！
Akid.
阿基德。
Dad.
爸爸。
Dad, what's wrong?
爸爸，怎么了？
Let's go, we've a lot to cover.
走吧，我们还有很多事情要做。
We're canceling the shopping trip.
我们取消购物之旅。
Let's just have a meal.
我们就吃顿饭吧。
Okay, we can.
好的，可以。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
But the more he went back…
但他越回去……
The worse my death became, right?
我的死法就更糟糕了，对吧？
He tried
他尝试过
so many times.
很多次了。
Multiple times.
多次。
Hundreds of times.
数百次。
Until
直到
he had
他有
to sacrifice himself
牺牲自己
to make sure that
以确保
you were okay.
你还好。
Thank you for coming.
谢谢您的到来。
I'm sorry for
我很抱歉
taking your time today.
今天请慢慢来。
This is my son,
这是我的儿子，
Rahim.
子宫。
He just finished his SPM exams.
他刚刚结束SP​​M考试。
I…
我…
I want to apologize to you.
我想向你道歉。
I really want to apologize to you.
我真的很想向你道歉。
The money you once gave me
你曾经给我的钱
changed my life.
改变了我的生活。
That money saved me.
那笔钱救了我。
That money also
那笔钱也
saved my child's life.
救了我孩子的命。
But…
但…
But what I've done to you--
但我对你所做的——
I forgive you.
我原谅你。
What?
什么？
Things that are meant to happen,
注定要发生的事情，
we can't prevent.
我们无法阻止。
Everything has been written.
一切都已写好。
Akid.
阿基德。
I know you want to express everything,
我知道你想表达一切，
but my job here
但我在这里的工作
is to evaluate your mental condition after
评估你的精神状况
your son's death.
你儿子的死。
Whatever it is,
不管是什么，
the government needs to know whether you're stable enough
政府需要知道你是否足够稳定
to continue your job.
继续你的工作。
What's your next plan?
你的下一步计划是什么？
Thank you, Kabir.
谢谢你，卡比尔。
For listening to my story.
感谢您聆听我的故事。
It's enough.
够了。
I know what I want to do next.
我知道我下一步想做什么。
Dad had to sacrifice himself
爸爸不得不牺牲自己
to make sure that you were okay.
确保你一切安好。
This is all I can help you with.
我能帮你的就这些了。
I should have
我应该
accepted the offer to Sabah.
接受了沙巴的邀请。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I just want you to know
我只是想让你知道
that I
我
love you very much.
非常爱你。
We always eat the same thing, right?
我们总是吃同样的东西，对吗？
Let's go out to eat?
我们出去吃饭吧？
Really?
真的吗？
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Have a good meal.
好好吃饭吧。
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
—谢谢。—不客气。
Anas, do you know?
阿纳斯，你知道吗？
This is the place
这个地方
your mom and I
你妈妈和我
used to come to often.
以前经常来。
This was our dating place.
这就是我们的约会地点。
Mom's favourite place.
妈妈最喜欢的地方。
That table at the back.
后面的那张桌子。
It was at that table
就在那张桌子上
we found out that we were going to be your parents.
我们发现我们将要成为你的父母。
The food here must be good, right?
这里的食物一定很好吃，对吧？
Eat.
吃。
I'm sorry, Anas.
对不起，阿纳斯。
to Anas.
致阿纳斯。
Did you forget my name?
你忘了我的名字吗？
Dad.
爸爸。
Anas, blow the candles.
阿纳斯，吹蜡烛。
Anas, what did you wish for?
阿纳斯，你许了什么愿？
I wanted an iPad but…
我想要一台 iPad 但是……
But what, love?
但什么，亲爱的？
Maybe just to spend time with both of you.
也许只是想和你们一起度过一段时光。
We'll go on a holiday.
我们将去度假。
Together with Mom, together with Anas.
和妈妈一起，和阿纳斯一起。
Anas.
阿纳斯。
-Wake up, Sarah. -Sarah, I can see his head.
—醒醒，莎拉。—莎拉，我能看到他的头。
A little more. Come, hurry.
还有一点。来，快点。
Sarah.
莎拉。
A little more. Come, Sarah.
再来一点。来吧，莎拉。
Okay, I can see his head, hurry.
好的，我能看到他的头了，快点。
Are we happy?
我们幸福吗？
The happiest in the world.
世界上最幸福的人。
With Anas.
和阿纳斯一起。
Anas?
阿纳斯？
Our son.
我们的儿子。
Very cute.
很可爱。
Looking sharp to meet your girlfriend?
期待与你的女朋友见面吗？
Eat a little.
吃一点儿。
Are you just going to have soup?
你只是喝汤吗？
There's mutton.
有羊肉。
Akid, hurry.
阿基德，快点。
Akid, you take half,
Akid，你拿一半，
I take half.
我占一半。
Akid.
阿基德。
Hey!
嘿！
Queue up, there are people behind.
排队吧，后面还有人。
There's a lot more.
还有更多。
Dad.
爸爸。
I'm sorry, Dad.
对不起，爸爸。
I know all this is wrong, Dad.
我知道这一切都是错的，爸爸。
But this is all I can do.
但这就是我所能做的一切。
I wanted to tell you,
我想告诉你，
I understand now, Dad.
我现在明白了，爸爸。
I understand why you didn't go back.
我明白你为什么不回去。
Why you
为什么你
made that decision.
做出了那个决定。
Because
因为
you wanted me to go on living.
你希望我继续活下去。
Akid.
阿基德。
Dad.
爸爸。
I am content, Dad.
我很满足，爸爸。
I'm content.
我很满足。
I had a family, Dad.
我有一个家庭，爸爸。
A wife.
一位妻子。
A son.
一个儿子。
Thank you, Dad,
谢谢你，爸爸，
for giving me a chance to experience
让我有机会体验
the beauty of life.
生命之美。
I know
我知道
according to fate,
根据命运，
I should've gone first
我应该先走
at the shopping mall.
在购物中心。
Dad, don't travel back anymore.
爸爸，你不要再回去了。
Don't fight fate.
不要与命运抗争。
I am already content.
我已经很满足了。
Oh, God.
哦，天哪。
Thank you, Dad,
谢谢你，爸爸，
for everything.
一切。
Akid.
阿基德。
Akid…
阿基德…
Enough.
足够的。
Don't, darling.
别这样，亲爱的。
We have to accept fate.
我们必须接受命运。
Just accept it.
接受它吧。
Tragedy at the Petaling Jaya shopping center.
八打灵再也购物中心发生悲剧。
Yesterday, an armed robbery took the life of a teenager.
昨天，一场武装抢劫夺走了一名青少年的生命。
Akid Bin Aziz, who tried to protect a pregnant female worker.
阿基德·本·阿齐兹 (Akid Bin Aziz) 试图保护一名怀孕的女工。
But unfortunately, the gunshot took his life.
但不幸的是，枪声夺走了他的生命。